http://www.expertrating.com/privacy/privacy.html

Last Updated: December 13th, 2017
If you have an unresolved privacy or data-use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third-party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at
https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request .
ExpertRating Solutions ("ExpertRating") is committed to protecting your privacy. We have established this privacy policy to communicate our information practices through this statement, pertaining to the collection, use and protection of the personal information we collect. This privacy policy applies exclusively to the website
www.expertrating.com, owned and operated by Expert Rating Solutions. By using this website, you are providing your consent to the privacy practices disclosed within this statement.
What type of user related information do we collect?
ExpertRating collects personal information from users of the website at different points of registration. Whether registering as affiliate partner, for an employer account or as an individual user, we collect personal information to facilitate your requested service. This collected personal information includes name, email and physical address, phone number, and PayPal I.D. where applicable. When you supply your credit card information, it is not retained on file by us. When users register for a ‘Live Proctored’ exam, we may also collect, during the proctored session, information such as a web cam photo I.D., a list of applications running on your system and geographical location, in order to maintain the integrity of the proctored session. You may contact us at ExpertRating Help Desk  to request for the removal of your information from our database.
Information collection during re-certification on ExpertRating - When you apply for re-certification, the website collects information related to your previous and current employment. You will be asked for your previous employer's address and current employer's address. This information is solely used for determining whether you are eligible for re-certification without re-taking the test.
How does ExpertRating use my information?
ExpertRating does not send any unsolicited messages to the registered users of the website. We use your collected information to register accounts, provide access to the services requested, process payments and provide customer service. ExpertRating reserves the right to send to users, notification, administrative and service emails, which are a part of the service. Consequently, you cannot opt out of these communications.
Our commitment to data security
Your personal information is kept strictly confidential through a security system, which only allows access to critical information to the company's security team members. This team consists of experienced engineers and staff who are under stringent confidentiality requirements. The security system is backed by the latest technology and ensures that your personal information is fully protected. Your ExpertRating profile, which is available to you in your login area, is protected through a password. You are advised to keep this password confidential and to ensure that you close the browser window after logging out from ExpertRating, especially if you are using a shared computer. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Therefore, while we do our utmost to protect your personal information, ExpertRating cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best efforts to ensure the security of your information on our systems.
Our commitment to payment information (credit card number) security
ExpertRating services can be purchased online through a secure credit card transaction using any major credit card or PayPal. The ecommerce functionality on the site has been provided by PayPal, which is a trusted name in online transaction processing. When you supply your credit card information, it is not retained on file by us. Moreover, the transaction takes place on the PayPal secure server, which is 100% safe and encrypts the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). When you buy any of our services, it is treated as a sale and your credit card will not be charged again in the future as is the case in subscription sales. These third-party agents do not share your sensitive information with any third parties and have no authorization to use your personal information for any unsolicited purposes.
How you can access or correct your personal information
ExpertRating Solutions will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. You can access and change the personal information that we collect and maintain by logging in to your user account with the username and passwords assigned to your account. You can delete your account and personal information by sending us a request through email or phone. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services, contact us at ExpertRating Help Desk. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.
The login page is at: https://www.expertrating.com/login.asp
To prevent unauthorized use of our testing services, you cannot change your username directly from the login area. You must request us for a change of name by clicking on the "request name change" link within your login area.
If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter, we will use your name and email address to send it to you. Out of respect for your privacy, you may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails or by accessing the email preferences in your account settings page or you can contact us at  ExpertRating HelpDesk .
Automatically Collected Information
ExpertRating and its partners use cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer the website, track users’ movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. You can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level, but if you choose to disable cookies, it may limit your use of certain features or functions on our website or service.
As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We may combine this automatically-collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to improve the services offered by us, to improve marketing, analytics, or site functionality.
We partner with a third party to either display advertisements on our website or to manage our advertisements on other websites. Our third-party partner may use technologies, such as cookies, to gather information about your activities on our website and other sites, in order to provide you advertisements based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt out by clicking here .  (or if located in the european union, click here ). please note that this does not opt you out of being served ads; you will continue to receive generic ads.
Information Sharing and Disclosure
In certain situations, ExpertRating Solutions may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including meeting national security or law enforcement requirements. We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. We do not sell your personal information to third parties. We may share your information with third parties who provide services on our behalf to help with our business activities. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.
ExpertRating may be required by law to disclose information to law enforcement, or other government agencies under certain circumstances such as in the event of a formal request made in a civil suit, court order, bankruptcy proceedings or subpoena served on the website. We reserve the right to disclose information in our sole and absolute discretion, where deemed necessary to protecting the safety of our staff, users, the general public, or in protecting our intellectual property.
Data Retention
We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services, contact us at  ExpertRating Help Desk. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.
Links to 3rd Party Sites
Our website includes links to other websites whose privacy practices may differ from those of ExpertRating Solutions. If you submit personal information to any of those websites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any website you visit.
Social Media Features
Our website includes social media features such as the Facebook Like button. These features may collect your IP address, information about the pages you visit on our website, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our website. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.
What is our policy if there is a change in our Privacy practices?
ExpertRating strives to improve the company's privacy policy from time to time. In the event of a material change, emails will automatically be sent out to all users, describing the changes in the privacy policy and how they can opt out from the effects of the new privacy policy. Users will clearly be given an opportunity to prohibit any use of information that was not described at the time the initial user information was collected. Moreover, the link to the updated privacy policy will be clearly mentioned on the home page of the site.
What is ExpertRating's policy if the site is sold or merged with another
company?
ExpertRating will do its utmost to ensure that the successor adheres to the same privacy policy. However, the privacy practices of the successor company cannot be ascertained before the eventuality of such a takeover. ExpertRating will do its best to inform all the registered users about the changes in the privacy practices as soon as the information about the new policy is made available, by posting a notice on the website, or by sending users’ an email to this end.
Who should I contact if I have a Privacy related concern?
If you have any doubts or require clarifications related to the privacy of your information with us, please use our
contact form
to get in touch with us.
Contact Us
Company Name : ExpertRating Solutions
Physical address : Block D, Ground Floor, DLF IT Park, Chandigarh-160101, India
Phone Number and email address : +91-172-4656989, contact(at)expertrating.com
